Guide to the Sallie Bingham Papers, 1900-2023 and undated RL.00112
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Poetry Series, 1977-1997
  - Electronic Format Poetry Subseries, 1994-1997 and undated
    - Finches, Finches.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Finding the River Again, River.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Fire Ring, Fire.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Firing Too Hot, Firing.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - First Snow, Snow.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - First Wolf in Yellowstone, Wolf, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - The Formula that Makes a Christmas Tree Drink More Water, Tree.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - The Formula that Makes Trees Drink More Water, Trees.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - For Peter, 1954-1974, Peter.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - For Peter, 1954-1976, Peter.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - For the Next Guest, Guest, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Fox, the Navajo Silversmith, Fox.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - From the Old Wife to the New, Oldnew.poe, 1995 (on Disk007 and Disk008) and Wife.poe, undated (on Disk009) (Box 1)
    - George Rogers Clark or A Use for Old Houses, Clark.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Gifts, Gifts, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Good Friday, Good.poe, 1996 (on Disk010) and 1997 (on Disk003), Good.bk!, 1996 (on Disk010) and Seed.poe, 1996 (on Disk010) (Box 1)
    - Good Friday: Stations of the Cross, Seed.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Gros Ventre Range, Gros.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - The Guards' Chapel Bombing, Chapel.poe, 1995 (on Disk008) and 1996 (on Disk007) (Box 1)
    - Hades, Hades.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Herakles Knot, Hera.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - The High Cost of Denying Rivers their Floodplains, Highcost, undated, on Disk021 (Box 1)
    - Holy Saturday: Eve Sees Jesus Descending Into Hell, Saturday.poe, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Holy Saturday: Jesus Descends Into Hell, Friday.poe, 1996, on Disk010 (Box 1)
    - The Hose is a Stubborn Soul, Hose.poe, 1994, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - In Aline's Garden, Aline.poe, 1994, on Disk015 (Box 1)
    - In How Many Rooms, Rooms.poe, 1996 (on Disk008) and Poppy.poe, undated (on Disk009) (Box 1)
    - In the Monks' Kitchen, Kitchen.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - In the Monks Kitchen: 11, Kitchen.poe, 1996 (on Disk010) and Kitchen1, 1997 (on Disk003) (Box 1)
    - July, July.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Kenosis, Kenosis.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Kerosine Lamps, Lamp.poe, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Kiss, Kiss, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Lake Cumberland, Cumber.poe, 1995, on Disk007 and Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Lap Bomb, Lapbomb.poe, 1995, on Disk007 and Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Lent, Lenti, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Let Me Go Call Olga, Olga.poe, 1994 (on Disk015) and 1995 (on Disk008) (Box 1)
    - Letter, Letter.poe, 1995 (on Disk007) and 1996 (on Disk008) (Box 1)
    - Like Ostriches in the Wilderness, Ostriche.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - The Man Who Can Do, Shears.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Mesa, Mesa.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Miracle, Miracle.poe, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Missies, Misies.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Mortgage, Mortgage, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Mother, Memorial, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Mount Moriah, Moriah.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - My Desire is Leaving, Desire.poe, 1995 (on Disk008) and 1996 (on Disk007) (Box 1)
    - My Father's Little Girl, Girl.poe, 1995 (on Disk008) and 1996 (on Disk007) (Box 1)
    - My Mother, Aged Ninety and her Great-Granddaughter, Ariadne, Mother.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - My Parents, Flying, Parents.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Naked Above Granite Falls, Naked.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - The New Graves, Carrots, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - The New House, House.bk!, 1996, on Disk010 (Box 1)
    - 1941-1945, 1941.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - No More Bones, Bones.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - November, Novemer.poe, 1995, on Disk007 and Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Oakland, Kentucky, Oakland.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Ohio River Winter, Hunters.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Oil Lamp, Lamp.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Once More, Oncemore.poe, 1994, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Order, Order.poe, undated, on Disk009 (Box 1)
    - Our Ancestors Were All Under the Cloud, Cloud.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Overseas, Overseas.poe, 1995 (on Disk008) and 1996 (on Disk007) (Box 1)
    - Persephone, Persephon, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Photograph, Toad.poe, undated, on Disk009 (Box 1)
    - A Picture of my Grandmother, Aged Ninety, and her Granddaughter Ariadne, Spider.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Pilgrim's Seat, Spoletto, Seat.poe, 1994, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Plaza Cerro, Cerro.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Pollen Stain, Pollen.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Pre-Revolutionary America, Prerev.poe, undated, on Disk009 (Box 1)
    - The Pueblo Rebellion: August 10, 1680, Pueblo.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Rainy Morning, Red.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Rest, Rest, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Reversing the Horseshoe, Old.poe, 1996 (on Disk010) and 1997 (on Disk003) (Box 1)
    - Road, Road.poe, 1995 (on Disk007), 1996 (on Disk008), and undated (on Disk009) (Box 1)
    - Roadside, Ely, Minnesota, Ely, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Rose, Rose.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Runaway, Runaway.poe, undated, on Disk009 (Box 1)
    - Seasoning, Season.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Seeding the Clouds, Seeding.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - She Finds Herself Alone, Curse.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Sic Transit in Deo Mater Christi, Mater.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Shenandoah, Shenandoa.poe, 1995 (on Disk008) and 1996 (on Disk007) (Box 1)
    - Shenandoan, Shenad.poe, undated, on Disk009 (Box 1)
    - Skiing Without Poles, Ski.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Snakebite, Snake.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Snapper, Snapper.poe, 1995 (on Disk007 and Disk008); Snapp.poe, undated, on Disk009 (Box 1)
    - Snow on the Coal, Coal.poe, 1993, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Sodomy, Sodomy.poe, 1994, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - South China Sea, Southchi.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Spanish Market, Saints.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - St. Francis Cathedral, Stfran.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Stockpile, Stockpil, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Swimming in the Chippewa Falls Y, Chippewa, 1995 (on Disk007 and Disk008) and Swim.poe, undated (on Disk009) (Box 1)
    - Taking Pictures, Pict.poe, 1994 (on Disk009), 1995 (on Disk008) and 1996 (on Disk015) (Box 1)
    - Thomas Eakins: The Gross Clinic, Eakins.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Tilma, Tilma.poe, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Tokens of their Esteem, Tokens, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Tom Softly, Softly.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Towpath, Towpath.poe, 1995 (on Disk008) and 1996 (on Disk007) (Box 1)
    - Transgression, Transgre.poe, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Tridentine Mass, Mass, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Trying to Attract a Hummingbird, Hummers.poe, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Trying to Attract Hummingbirds, Hummers.poe, 1994, on Disk015 (Box 1)
    - Two Girls, Girls.poe, 1996 (on Disk007) and 1997 (on Disk008) (Box 1)
    - Uranus Enters Aquariums, Uranus, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Uses of the Bidet, Bidet.poe, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - War Time, Wartime.poe, 1995 (on Disk008) and 1996 (on Disk007) (Box 1)
    - Washington 1941, Wash.poe, 1995 (on Disk008) and 1996 (on Disk007) (Box 1)
    - Water Boy, Water.poe, 1996 (on Disk010) and 1997 (on Disk003) (Box 1)
    - Why There Are No Shells in Key West, Shells.poe, 1994, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - The Willingness to Undo Knots, Knots, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - The Winter Gives, Winter.poe, 1994, on Disk009 (Box 1)
    - Wolf Killer, Wolfkill, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 1)
    - Writing to Jail, Jail.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Wyoming Road Map, Map.poe, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 1)
    - Notes (poem fragments and ideas), Poems.not, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 1)
- Santa Fe Stages Series, 1994-1998 (RESTRICTED)
  Contains various materials related to the founding and functioning of Santa Fe Stages, a regional theater founded by Bingham in Santa Fe, New Mexico. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Budget, 1998-1999 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Financial and legal papers, 1994-1998 (Box 1)
  - Fundraising (Box 1)
  - Publicity, 1995-1999 (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - Resignation of Martin Platt, 1998 (Box 1)
- Speeches Series, 1959, 1980-1998 and undated
  Contains the text of speeches given by Bingham to various women's groups, civic organizations, and educational associations. Speech topics cover a range of feminist issues, many based on Bingham's own experiences with the sale of Bingham Enterprises. Topics include women in the board room, feminist philanthropy, women's writing and the politics of publishing. The bulk of the speeches were given from the mid-1980s through the early 1990s, at which time Bingham decided to reduce the number of her public appearances. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Border Book Festival, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Material for Speeches (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
  - 1980-1989 (7 folders arranged chronologically) (Box 1)
  - 1990-1998 (4 folders arranged chronologically) (Box 1)
- Subject Files Series, 1930-1998
  Miscellaneous files which reflect various social, political and literary activities of Bingham and her family. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Al-Anon's Blueprint for Progress, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Amazon.com (Box 1)
  - Articles about and interviews with Bingham, 1958-1997 (Box 1)
  - Bingham genealogy (Box 1)
  - Bingham Plays: rehearsed readings, undated (Box 1)
  - The Binghams of Louisville by David Chandler
    - Chronology (Box 1)
    - Draft: marked text (Box 1)
    - Legal memorandum from Barry Bingham, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Blue Mountain Center, undated (1 folder)
    - Mementos, 1989 (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Broomstick, No. 4, Autumn 1993 (Box 1)
  - Bunting Institute Appointment, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Celebrating Women, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Celebrating Women: A Commemorative Journal, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Censorship and Libel (Box 1)
  - The Center for Women and Families (Box 1)
  - The Community Foundation: Annual Report, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Craft Motor Vehicle Negligence Action (Box 1)
  - The Farm (Box 1)
  - First Annual Women's Policy Research Conference Proceedings, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Five Year Plan, 1990-1995 (Box 1)
  - Funding Exchange, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Goddesses (Box 1)
  - Hamburger, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Hiring and Tenure of Women at Harvard/Radcliffe (Box 1)
  - House of Dreams by Marie Brenner, 1988-1991 (Box 1)
  - Indiana University Information (Box 1)
  - Institute for Women's Policy Research Discussion Paper, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Interview with Bonnie Cox, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Jesse Jackson Campaign, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Joan Bingham (Box 1)
  - MacDowell Colony, undated (1 folder)
    - Drawings, 1990 (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Matthew Shepard death, 1998 (Box 1)
  - "Mind Torn--Spirit Broken" (M.A. thesis of Emily Simms Bingham) 1990 (Box 1)
  - The Missoula Colony, undated (Box 1)
  - New Girl in Town (performance), undated (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1930s-1940s (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1952-1980 (Box 1)
  - Next Stage, Inc. (financial report), 1994 (Box 1)
  - The Patriarch by Jones and Tifft, 1986-1991 (Box 2)
  - Patty Smith (Box 2)
  - Paulette Rose Rare Book Catalogue (Box 2)
  - Political Causes (Box 2)
  - Readings, undated (Box 2)
  - Real Estate/Cars (Box 2)
  - Religious Worship, 1989-1997 (Box 2)
  - Resume and biographical information (Box 2)
  - Sadie Ruth Lawing (Box 2)
  - Santa Fe Reporter Sale, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Sarabande Books (Box 2)
  - Second Stages Proposal (Box 2)
  - Shaman Studies (Box 2)
  - Shoe String Theater, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Speeches (by Mary Bingham and Barry Bingham, Sr.) (Box 2)
  - Submissions, 1982-1990
    - 1991-1992 (Box 2)
    - 1988-1998 (Box 2)
    - Poetry and miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
  - Taos Art School (Box 2)
  - Theater of the Immaculate Conception (Box 2)
  - Travel (Box 2)
  - Virginia Center for the Creative Arts Fellows List, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Women and Publishing (Box 2)
  - Women in Theater (Box 2)
  - Women's Center (Louisville, Ky.) (Box 2)
  - Work by Chris Iovenko, Barry Ellsworth, Robert Bingham (Box 2)
  - Workshops, undated (Box 2)
  - Zoland Books catalogs (Box 2)
- Writings Series, 1953-1998 and undated
  This largest series in the collection contains drafts and published copies of all of Sallie Bingham's literary writings, including her poems, short stories, plays, novels as well as essays and book reviews. There is a significant amount of material devoted to her memoir Passion and Prejudice as well as to her many novels. Files are arranged alphabetically by the title of the work and many include related research files, correspondence with publishers or producers, contracts, letters from well-wishers, and copies of reviews or publicity. At the end of the series are miscellaneous files pertaining to Bingham's writing, including proposed projects, newspaper clippings for research and book reviews.
  Many of Bingham's writings were received as electronic files. If an individual work has a corresponding electronic file, an entry for the file is included in the alphabetical list below. In such cases, following an individual work's title there is a brief description, then the electronic file's name, the year in which the file was last modified, and the file's disk (subdirectory) name. A number of these works exist in more than one iteration; these may have multiple file names and/or reside in multiple subdirectories. Note that many of the following works possess multiple files that may have been created or edited in different years. Disks were assigned consecutive numbers reflecting the original order in which they were received.
  [The contents of each disk was migrated to a library server. Please consult a reference archivist for access to the electronic files.]
  - Acequia Madre, undated (Box 1)
    - Draft, Acequia.ss, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 1)
    - Title page, Ace.tit, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 1)
  - The Act, ca. 1979 (Box 1)
  - Addicts, 1977 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - After Such Knowledge, 1960 (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - Against Her Grain, undated (Box 1)
  - The Age of Enlightenment, 1989 (Box 1)
  - And the Band Played On, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Ann Clifton, undated (Box 1)
  - The Appraisal, ca. 1980s (Box 1)
  - Art, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Art of the Migration Period, undated (poetry) (Box 1)
  - Assyrians, undated
    - Draft, Assyrian, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 1)
    - Title, Ass.Tit, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 1)
  - At Home in Harrodsburg, 1980s (Box 1)
  - At the Abortionist's, undated (Box 1)
  - August Ninth at Natural Bridge, undated (Box 1)
  - The Awakening, 1987-1989
    - Correspondence and contract (Box 1)
    - Draft, 1988 (7 folders) (Box 1)
    - Draft, 1989 (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - Horse Cave production, 1989
      - Draft for Horse Cave production (Box 2)
      - Production file (Box 2)
      - Rehearsal notes (Box 2)
    - Notes, research, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Back Seat Driving, 1989-1991 (Box 2)
  - Bambi in Paris, 1958-1996
    - Draft, Bambi.doc, 1997, on Disk023 (Box 2)
  - Bare Bones, 1965, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Barerooted (poetry, in electronic format only), 1997
    - Table of contents, Bare.tit, 1997, on Disk003 (Box 2)
  - Bat, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Beach Daze, ca. 1980s (Box 2)
  - Beginning, undated (Box 2)
  - Beyond Despair, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Bicentennial Baby, 1995
    - Draft, Baby.pla, 1995, on Disk009 (Box 2)
  - The Big Day, undated (Box 2)
  - The Birthday Party, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Biting the Hand: A Woman and a Family Empire, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Blackbird, 1991
    - Drafts and editing notes, Blackb~1.doc, 1996, on Disk023 and Disk024 (Box 2)
  - Blank Check, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Blind Love, 1991
    - Drafts, Blindlov.ss, 1996, on Disk022 and Disk024 (Box 2)
  - The Blue Glass Pin, 1996-1997
    - Title page, Glass.tit, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 2)
  - Blueberries, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Boy, Dreaming, ca. late 1980s (Box 2)
  - The Boy in the Bathrobe, undated
    - Draft, Boy.ss, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 2)
  - Bride Doll, undated (Box 2)
  - Bright Lights, 1986 (Box 2)
  - The Brightest Girl in the Class, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Called Away, 1980s (Box 2)
  - The Candidate's Lady, ca. 1994 (1 folder)
    - Draft, ca. 1994 (1 folder) (Box 3)
  - The Candidate's Wife, undated (3 folders)
    - Draft, Wife.doc, 1996, on Disk017 (Box 3)
  - Captain Bud, 1984
    - Drafts, captbud.doc, 1996, on Disk023 and Disk024 (Box 3)
  - Celia, ca. 1988
    - Drafts, celia.doc, 1996, on Disk023 and Disk024 (Box 3)
  - A Certain Stream, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Charlie, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Chaucer and Mystery, undated
    - Draft, Chauc, 1993, on Disk013 (Box 3)
  - Childbirth, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Children of Cronus, ca. 1985 and undated (5 folders)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
    - Draft of Act One, Cronus1.doc, 1997, on Disk023 (Box 3)
    - Draft of Act Two, Cronus2.doc, 1996, on Disk023 (Box 3)
    - Synopsis, Cronus, 1993 (on Disk013) and Cronus.syn, 1995 (on Disk023) (Box 3)
  - Choosing, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Christ in the Desert, undated
    - Drafts, Christ.ss, 1994 (on Disk015) and Christ.ss!, 1997 (on Disk024) (Box 3)
  - CIA, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Cold Comfort, ca. 1997 (Box 3)
  - Consolations, undated
    - Drafts, consolation.doc, 1996 (on Disk023) and Consol~1.doc, 1996 (on Disk024) (Box 3)
  - Cory's Feast, 1993 (1 folder)
    - Draft, 1995 (4 folders) (Box 3)
    - Draft of chapter one, Ch1.cf, 1993, on Disk005 (Box 3)
    - Drafts of miscellaneous chapters, 1993 (on Disk021), 1995 and 1996 (on Disk006) (Box 3)
    - Draft of part two, Cf.p2, 1995, on Disk008 (Box 3)
    - Draft, part 2, 1995-1996 (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Draft, undated (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Notes, 1993 (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Notes, Cf.not, 1995, and Cory.que, 1996, on Disk006 (Box 4)
    - Prologue, Pro-cf.asc, 1993, on Disk021 (Box 4)
    - Quote and Prologue, Dedi.cor, Pro.cor, and Quote.cf, 1995, on Disk006 (Box 4)
    - Title page, Title, 1995, on Disk006 (Box 4)
  - The Country Boy, ca. 1980s (Box 4)
  - Country Western, undated (Box 4)
  - Couvade, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Creating Totems, ca. 1991 (Box 4)
  - Crossing the Alps, 1989-1992 (Box 4)
  - Cruise, ca. 1985 (Box 4)
  - Curious Castle, ca. 1988
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Custer's Revenge, undated (Box 4)
  - Dancing, undated (Box 4)
  - The Darkness and the Light, ca. 1985 (3 folders)
    - Research and correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 4)
  - Dark Speech (in electronic format only), 1996
    - List of published stories, Index, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 4)
    - Title page, Title.ds, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 4)
  - The Death of Henry Flagler, 1988 (5 folders)
    - Production file, 1988 (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Draft, 1992 (2 folder) (Box 4)
    - Draft, 1995 (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - Draft, 1995 (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Production file, 1995 (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - Draft, undated (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Deprivation Diaries, ca. 1997 (Box 5)
  - Desire, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Developing New Perspectives: Women Who Live Near Power, undated (Box 5)
  - Djalioh, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Do Not Acknowledge/Do Not Respond, undated (poetry) (Box 5)
  - Doing Good, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Doing Without Them, undated (Box 5)
  - Dragon's Teeth, ca. 1993
    - Draft, Dragons.ss, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 5)
  - The Dress is Fitted, undated (Box 5)
  - Dusty Miller, undated (Box 5)
  - Easter, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Elizabeth's Long Sleep, undated
    - Draft, Sleep.ss, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 5)
  - Evelyn Scott: The Limitations of the Search for Truth, ca. 1980 (Box 5)
  - Evidence, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Exiles (genesis of Upstate), undated (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - The Facts of His Life, undated (Box 5)
  - Falling in Love Again: New York, Winter, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Family, undated (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - A Family Chorus, undated (Box 5)
  - The Family of the Future, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Fear, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Feather, undated
    - Draft, Feather.ss, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 5)
  - A Few Thoughts on Breast Feeding, undated (Box 5)
  - The Fiest, 1988
    - Draft, fiest.doc, 1996, on Disk023 (Box 5)
  - Finding My Mothers, undated (Box 5)
  - First Born, 1988, 1990 (Box 5)
  - The Flavor of Solitude, undated (Box 5)
  - Flood, ca. 1990
    - Draft, flood.doc, 1996, on Disk023 (Box 5)
  - Fresh Salmon, 1998 (Box 5)
  - The Frog Prince, undated (Box 5)
  - Frozen, 1997
    - Drafts, Frozen.ss, 1997, on Disk018 and Disk024 (Box 5)
  - Games, undated (Box 5)
  - Getting Lost Together, undated (Box 5)
  - Gift Horse, 1993-1994
    - Draft, Gifthors.ss, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 5)
  - Girl Alone, 1974 (Box 6)
    - Draft, Girlal~1.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 6)
  - Going Away, undated
    - Draft, Goinga~1.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 6)
  - Going Native, 1993-1997
    - Draft and note, Native.ss, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 6)
  - The Gold Piece, undated (Box 6)
  - Gold Star Mothers, 1989 (Box 6)
  - The Golden Now, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Good, undated (Box 6)
  - The Good Mother, 1993
    - Draft, Goodma, 1993, on Disk013 (Box 6)
  - Good-bye to All That: Another Southerner Quits the South, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Growing Up Episcopalian, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Guns, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Gypsies, 1984
    - Drafts, Gypsies.doc, 1996 (on Disk019 and Disk024), gypsies.doc, 1996 (on Disk023) and Gypsies.ss, 1996 (on Disk024) (Box 6)
  - The Hall Tree, undated (Box 6)
  - Hand to Heart, 1996
    - Draft, Handto~1.doc, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 6)
  - A Handmade Life, undated (Box 6)
  - A Handmade Life, undated (Box 6)
  - Heroic Measures, undated (3 folders)
    - Synopsis and play (1 folder) (Box 6)
  - The High Cost of Denying Rivers their Floodplains, 1996 (poetry)
    - Draft and title page, Highcost, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 6)
  - His Sons, undated
    - Draft, Boys, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 6)
  - History, undated
    - Draft, History.ss, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 6)
  - Hopscotch, 1986 (7 folders)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Draft and title page, Hop.sal, 1988, on Disk001 (Box 6)
    - Horse Cave Production (Box 6)
    - Research files (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Reviews (Box 6)
  - Hot River (in electronic format only), 1997
    - Draft, Hot.bk!, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 6)
  - How to Make Friends with a Man, 1993 (Box 6)
  - I am the Resurrection and the Life, 1997
    - Drafts, Resurr~1.doc, 1996, on Disk018, Disk023 and Disk024 (Box 6)
  - The Ice Party, 1963 (Box 7)
  - If Sulzberger, 1990 (Box 7)
  - I'm Concerned for You, 1997 (Box 7)
  - In Boston, 1987
    - Draft, boston.doc, 1996, on Disk021 (Box 7)
  - In the Back Bay, 1970s (Box 7)
  - In the Midst, undated
    - Draft, Midst.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 7)
  - In the Presence, undated (3 folders)
    - Draft, 1991 (5 folders) (Box 7)
    - Production and review file, 1986, 1990-1993 (1 folder) (Box 7)
  - In the Yurt, ca. 1979 (1 folder)
    - Early Times production, 1979 (1 folder) (Box 7)
  - Intervention, 1986 (Box 7)
  - The Iron Age, ca. 1982
    - Drafts, Ironage.doc, 1996 (on Disk019 and Disk024) and ironage.doc, 1996, (on Disk023) (Box 7)
  - The Island, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Jack and the North West Wind, ca. 1992 (Box 7)
  - Jake Brakes and Rumble Strips: A Road Trip Through the West, ca. 1996 (2 folders; poetry)
    - Drafts, Jakebrak, 1996, on Disk003 and Disk008 (Box 7)
    - Title page, Tit.jak, 1996, on Disk003 (Box 7)
  - Jeff Co, 1991
    - Drafts, Jeff, 1996 (on Disk014 and Disk015) and 1997 (on Disk024) (Box 7)
  - Joy, undated (Box 7)
  - Julia Peterkin: At a Loss for Words, ca. late 1980s (Box 7)
  - Kitchen Thoughts, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Labor Day, undated
    - Draft, Laborday, 1995, on Disk024 (Box 7)
  - Lambing Moon, 1993 (Box 7)